Right, let's download it!
对 我们下载吧
Okay, you're under arrest.
好了 你被捕了
NO MORE PIRATING MOVIES
（禁止盗摄电影）
Coming.
来了
Can I help you?
有什么事吗？
-Are you Ryohei Yamada? -Yes.
-你是山田辽平先生吗？ -对
Your arrest warrant.
这是你的逮捕令
What?
什么？
-We're back now. -We're back.
-我们回来了
Welcome home.
欢迎回来
Going out?
你要出门吗？
-Yeah. For an interview. -What?
-对 去会面 -什么？
JLSC requested a court-appointed lawyer.
日本司法支援中心 请我们担任义务辩护律师
They did, huh?
来了吗？
Court-appointed lawyer?
义务辩护是什么？
If a suspect or a defendant--
如果嫌疑人或被告
…can't afford a lawyer because they have no assets,
因为没有资产而请不起律师
the country appoints one for them.
国家就会指派一个给他们
The appointed lawyer or defendant can't refuse unless there's a good reason.
被指定的律师或嫌犯 如果没有充分理由是不能拒绝的
I see.
原来如此
On top of that,
最重要的是
it's cheap!
很便宜
If we do all we can for the case, we may end up in the red.
这个案子如果全力以赴的话 最后一定会以赤字收场
What's the case?
这次是什么案件？
Defending a man who pirated a movie.
为盗摄电影的男子辩护
What?
什么？
His arrest is getting attention online. It's a chance to sell myself.
嫌犯遭到逮捕在网络上引起骚动 这是自我宣传的好机会
Oh.
哦
Don't!
不可以
If you focus on your publicity, it could cause problems.
一想到要宣传就会出问题
Here we go.
又来了
-Make sure to-- -Understood!
-注意你的言行… -知道了
I'll be off.
我要出门了
-See you later. -See you.
-路上小心
Huh? You're not going?
嗯？你不去吗？
No, I'm not.
不 我不用
Unfortunately, paralegals are considered unqualified in the Japanese legal world.
很遗憾 律师助理在日本法律界 被视为不具任何资格
So they can't attend interviews.
所以不能去会面
Even in the courtroom, they can only sit in the spectators' seats.
即使上法院 也只能坐在旁听席
But Haneo seemed motivated, so he'll be--
不过看羽男先生这么积极 一个人也…
That's why I'm worried.
所以我才担心
He may do something to cause trouble for the firm.
他可能会做一些奇怪的事情 造成律所的麻烦
WEAR GLASSES. I MAY LOOK MORE LIKE A GENIUS.
（戴眼镜 可能会更像天才）
YAHOGAWA POLICE STATION
（谷保川警察局）
Sorry to keep you waiting.
久等了
I'm Haneoka, your defense counsel.
我是帮你辩护的律师 我姓羽根冈
Hello.
你好
I'm sure you have a lot of concerns,
我想你一定很不安
but let's build a trusting relationship. Okay?
不过我们先建立起信赖关系 好吗？
-Okay. -Good.
-好
Alright, let me confirm.
好 让我确认一下
Mr. Ryohei Yamada. You are a 23-year-old, aspiring film director.
山田辽平先生 你今年23岁 一心想当上电影导演
You made independent movies in a college film club and
你在大学电影社拍过独立电影
uploaded them to "Yamada-chan Channel," your own video-sharing website.
并上传到自己的视频分享网站 “山田酱频道”
Yes.
是
One day, you were watching a movie for studying purposes.
有一天 你为了研究目的 看了一部有趣的电影
Since it was good, you wanted to share with the staff.
想要跟工作人员分享
You downloaded and edited the movie into a ten-minute clip and uploaded it
于是下载这部电影 并剪辑成10分钟的短片
to "Yamada-chan Channel" for members-only access.
以会员限定的形式 上传到“山田酱频道”
Right.
对
You've uploaded movie summary videos to "Yamada-chan Channel" since then.
之后也时常把电影剪成短片 上传到“山田酱频道”
But five months ago,
五个月前
you mistakenly uploaded one to the public and not to limited users.
你不小心把一支会员限定的电影 设定成了一般公开
To your surprise, it reached 10,000 views overnight
让你惊讶的是 一夜之间播放量就达到一万次
and it went up to 200,000 views in a few days.
几天之后更是达到20万次
The response was incomparable
反响太热烈了
to the independent movies you've released in the past.
你之前放上网络的 独立电影根本不能比
You received grateful comments, such as "This is what I needed,"
很多人还留言感谢你 “这就是我想看的”
and "It's great when I don't have much time."
“时间不多时很有帮助”
The number of your channel subscribers also shot up.
频道订阅人数更是一路攀升
Yup.
对
So, you started posting summary videos of movies that have already been released,
于是你开始将已经上映的电影 剪成解说剧情的短片
which are also known as "fast movies"--
也就是所谓的“快电影” 陆续上传…
Then the police suddenly showed up and I was shocked.
然后警察就突然找上门 我吓坏了
Right.
对
And you uploaded 27 videos in total. Correct?
你总共上传了27个视频 对吧？
I guess.
应该是吧
Okay.
好
And Zipangu Pictures, a film company that produced nine of those movies
制作其中九部电影的公司 “日本影业”
have sued you for violation of the Copyright Act.
以违反著作权法对你提出告诉
Seems like it.
看来是这样
Well, yes. Um…
也是 嗯…
Your account has been suspended and you've been arrested too.
现在你的账号遭到冻结 本人也被逮捕
I'm sure you're regretting--
我想你一定很后悔…
What? Why?
什么？为什么？
Huh?
嗯？
Regret what?
后悔什么？
Excuse me?
什么？
I'm just annoyed.
我只是很生气
What's wrong with fast movies?
快电影有什么问题吗？
As I said, the copyright--
就说了 违反著作权…
My videos aren't monetized. It's not about making money.
我的视频又没有营利 这么做也不是为了赚钱
So it's fine, no?
有什么不好？
Times have changed.
今时不同往日了
No one will watch paid content if they don't know the plot.
不知道里面有什么情节的付费内容 根本没有人要看
Also, fewer people go to the cinema today.
进电影院的人也越来越少
But the people who saw my videos said they've come to like movies.
但别人看了我的视频后 都说他们现在喜欢上电影了
So, what's the problem?
有什么问题吗？
What's wrong with him?
那家伙有什么毛病？
Zero! Seriously!
完全没有
-Zero remorse. -Keep your voice down.
-根本没反省 -小声一点
I hate dealing with guys like that.
我讨厌跟这种人打交道
Lawyer Ethics!
律伦
-So, it's him. -Huh?
-是他 -什么？
I was annoyed because he also uploaded my favorite director's movies.
他也有上传我喜欢的导演拍的电影 让我很生气
What's his name?
导演叫什么名字？
Kyohei Yamada.
山田恭兵
Isn't that the suspect?
那不是嫌犯吗？
That's Ryohei Yamada.
嫌犯叫山田辽平
Kyohei is a late-blooming director, who's almost 70 years old.
恭兵先生已经快70岁了 是大器晚成的导演
But he recently won an international award and is gaining popularity.
最近赢得国际大奖 逐渐受到一些人的好评
I see.
原来如此
The suspect is his fan too.
嫌犯好像也是他的粉丝
He watched his movies because their names are alike and wants to be a director too.
因为名字很像 所以看了电影 结果迷上了 才立志要当导演
Even more unforgivable if he's a fan.
如果是粉丝就更不可原谅了
I want to settle this out of court for a dismissal, but…
为了争取不起诉 我想要达成庭外和解 但是…
That would be difficult.
应该很困难吧
Thanks for waiting.
久等了
Here you go.
好
Kakesoba for Shoko.
荞麦汤面是硝子的
Thank you.
谢谢
Kamo Nanban for you.
葱鸭荞麦面是你的
Here's your Zaru.
你的是凉面
This is on the house.
这次店里请客
Really?
可以吗？
-Thank you. -No!
-谢谢 -不是啦
You scared me.
吓到我了
It's for Shoko.
是招待硝子的
Sorry?
什么？
Look at where the plate is. It's not for you guys.
看我放盘子的位置也知道 没有要招待你们
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
A-All of them?
全部都给她？
Yup, all for her.
全部…
Let's eat.
我要开动了
-Let's eat.
-我要开动了
Oh, wait.
等等
Did you just blow on it?
你刚刚吹了吧？
Of course not.
怎么可能
I saw you do it.
不 你吹了
I didn't.
我没吹
Your face said it all.
你的表情说明了一切
-I didn't. -You did.
-我没吹 -明明就有
Who did?
你说谁？
You did.
你啊
I blew on it?
我吹了吗？
-Yes. -I didn't.
-你吹了 -我没吹
We were hoping Zipangu Pictures would agree to a settlement.
我方希望日本影业能同意和解
In the first place, the suspect didn't receive any profit from this.
首先 这次案件 嫌疑人本身并没有获益
This is not about money.
不是钱的问题
The reason for this lawsuit is to have a judicial decision against
而是希望司法对快电影这种犯罪行为 做出适当判决
the criminal act of fast movies and for the public to recognize that.
让社会大众认知到后果 这才是我们提出告诉的目的
There will be no settlement.
我们不会和解的
Turned out exactly the way we expected.
想也知道会这样
Indeed.
的确
WASEDA
（早稻田）
INDICTMENT
（起诉书）
Now that he's been indicted,
既然都被起诉了
all we can do is to try and get a suspended sentence.
现在只能尽量争取缓刑了
For that to happen, the defendant must express his remorse.
为此 被告必须表明有反省的意思
For my sake too.
这也是为了我
My social media is blowing up with people telling me not to defend him.
帮那家伙辩护 我在社交媒体上被骂翻了
-Don't defend him. -How much are you getting paid?
-“为何帮他辩护” -“包庇罪犯 到底拿了多少钱？”
-Quit your job. -Just as guilty!
-“律师别干了吧” -“你也一样有罪”
He looks stupid.
“脑袋坏掉了吗？”
Why did it turn out this way?
怎么会变成这样？
-Ouch. -Here.
-哎哟 -请用
Oh, thanks.
谢谢
I'll make him feel remorse to calm this down.
为了平息争议 我一定要让他好好反省
But will he feel remorse?
他会反省吗？
I doubt it.
应该不会吧
What?
什么？
It doesn't matter if he really is sorry.
有没有真的反省又不重要
What's important is for him to say he's sorry in court.
在法庭上表现出反省的意思 这才是重点
Is that good enough?
这样就可以了吗？
If it's not genuine remorse, his future will--
如果不是真的反省 对他以后的人生…
Do I have to get involved that far?
我有必要这么投入吗？
Didn't she complain that being a court appointed lawyer will put us in the red?
她不是才抱怨说 义务辩护会造成赤字什么的？
-Yes. -Well, it would be a problem.
-对 -造成赤字的话的确会很困扰
Right? Now, now.
对吧？好了…
Just watch how I do it.
你就好好看我表现吧
TOKYO DETENTION CENTER, VISITING ROOM
（东京拘留所 会面室）
And for that reason, it's important for you to show remorse.
就是因为这样 表现出反省的意思是很重要的
Okay.
好
Here's a list of potential arguments. Could you memorize the answers?
我这里准备了模拟问答 可以请你背下来吗？
You went too far due to your love of movies.
因为太热爱电影 一不小心做得太过火了
That's our plan.
我们就走这个路线吧
Okay.
好
Let's read this once, shall we? Together.
先念过一遍吧 我们一起
So, if they ask "Are there any errors in the indictment?"
被问到“起诉书内容是否有误”时
You say…
你说
"No, I did it."
“没错 是我做的”
There are no errors in the indictment.
起诉书内容完全没有错
I know that my actions have hurt a lot of people
我知道这样做伤害了很多人
and caused a lot of trouble.
也给很多人带来了麻烦
My actions were thoughtless and I am deeply regre…
这样的行为太过草率了 我深切反省…
But actually, what's the problem?
到底哪里有问题？
I really don't get it.
我真的不懂
Mr. Yamada.
山田先生
It's the same as trailers.
就跟预告片一样吧
Even if it's made by someone who doesn't own the rights,
即使是没有版权的人做的
it ends up promoting the movie.
最后还是帮电影宣传了
And introducing classic movies contributes to the film industry in general.
介绍经典电影 也能对电影产业有所贡献
It's all good.
好处多多哦
Come on. Sit here.
过来这里 坐下
Let me ask you this.
我问问你
Is this how you do it?
这就是你的表现吗？
How did you advise him exactly?
你到底是怎么指导他的？
It was a devil.
是恶魔
What?
什么？
His T-shirt.
他穿的T恤
It was a horrifying devil.
图案是可怕的恶魔
That'll give a bad impression to the judges.
那会让法官留下糟糕的印象
Why that shirt?!
为什么要穿那件衣服？
I told him that too!
我也跟他说了
I said, "Let's not wear that, okay?"
“不要穿那件吧
"A white shirt and a jacket would be nice."
白衬衫搭配外套会比较好”
But apparently, it's his favorite because of some movie.
但是他说某部电影的主角也穿这件 他很喜欢
Since it's not just one or two copyright infringement lawsuits,
针对他侵害著作权的起诉 不是只有一两件
the defendant may not get a suspended sentence
被告要是不改变那种态度的话
unless he changes that attitude.
是争取不到缓刑的
If that happens, it will damage the lawyer and the firm in charge.
那样的话 可是会砸了辩护律师和律所的招牌
Damn!
可恶
Yoshio.
佳男
It's been a while.
好久不见了
You have a trial?
你今天出庭吗？
Well, yeah.
对
Good timing. Keep the 18th of next week open.
刚好跟你说一下 把下星期的18号空出来
Dad's birthday dinner. The judgment date was postponed, so he can come.
是爸爸的生日宴 判决日期延后了 所以他可以来
Okay.
好
Is she from your office?
律所的同事吗？
Yeah, she's the paralegal--
对 她是律师助理…
-Nice to meet you.
-幸会
Thank you for taking care of him. I'm his sister.
谢谢你照顾他 我是他姐姐
-Yuno Haneoka. -Thank you.
-我叫羽根冈优乃 -名片我收下了
I'm Shoko Ishida from Ushio Law Firm.
我是潮法律所的石田硝子
Thank you.
谢谢
Mr. Haneoka has been a great help to us.
一直以来都承蒙羽根冈律师的关照
What? Are you sure?
什么？你确定吗？
Then I guess you're keeping things hidden pretty well, huh?
看来很多事你都隐藏得很好 对吧？
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Please continue to look out for him.
今后还请继续关照我弟了
Sure, it's my pleasure.
没问题 不客气
-It was nice meeting you. -Likewise.
-幸会 -我也是
Nice glasses.
眼镜很好看
See you.
回见
So, your sister is a prosecutor.
你姐姐是检察官啊
Yeah.
是的
I overheard that your father is also in the legal world?
刚刚听她那么说 你爸也在法律界？
He's a judge.
他是法官
It's not like I wanted to take it.
我也不是自己想考才去考的
These exams are for your parents' benefit.
考试都是为了爸妈
Smells good.
好香
We're home.
我们回来了
-Welcome back! -Nice work.
-欢迎回来 -辛苦了
Wow.
哇
We're eating together today.
今天大家一起吃饭
Waterless tomato curry.
西红柿无水咖喱
With Brazilian enzymes.
加了巴西酵素
What experiment is this?
这是什么实验？
It's not an experiment. I'm just growing pea sprouts.
不是实验 只是在种豆苗
What?
什么？
You can eat them again if you grow them carefully.
吃完之后好好照顾 再次长出来就又能吃了
Maximum three times, though.
不过最多只能收成三次就是了
How stingy.
够节省的
Fine.
好吧
You won't be eating our pea sprouts anymore then.
以后你都不会吃我们家的豆苗吧
Please remember that.
请记住哦
Okay.
好吧
That's fine with me.
我没问题
Oh yeah, you two.
对了 两位
He turned defiant in court, right?
那家伙不是在法庭上大放厥词吗？
After watching that news,
看到那则新闻后
people who mistook Ryohei Yamada for Kyohei Yamada are criticizing him.
有人把山田辽平和山田恭兵导演搞混 还跑去骂人
Look at the official Twitter page of his new movie.
这是导演新片的官方推特
"Someone like him is making movies?"
“像他这种人还拍了电影？”
"Cancel the screening!" It's flooded with horrible comments.
“取消上映吧” 简直恶评如潮
Reality is brutal.
现实很残酷
There are too many idiots.
笨蛋太多了
This is the worst possible timing. We're the movie premieres tomorrow.
时间真是太不凑巧了 明天就是首映了
The reputational damage will be grave.
我们被流弹波及得太严重了
Why didn't you sue him for defamation in the first place?
是说您一开始 怎么没告那家伙毁谤呢？
Aren't you angry about how he edited your work?
导演的作品被这样恶搞 难道不会不甘心吗？
Of course he is.
他当然会不甘心
But we're a small production company. What can we do?
但我们只是一家小型制片公司 能怎么办呢？
TAINTED TOWING
（《污秽的曳航》）
I just want to focus on this movie right now.
现在我只想把心思放在这部电影上
-Yup. Right there. -Yeah?
-对 就是那里 -是吗？
It premieres tomorrow.
是明天首映
His new movie.
导演的新作
Right.
对
That's good.
不错
Oh, nice.
很舒服
There's a showing near here.
附近的影院也有上映
Okay.
好吧
There's a late-night show too.
也有晚上的场次
Is this an invitation?
你是在约我吗？
Oh… Yes.
哦…是啊
If you're interested, that is.
如果你有兴趣的话
I'm a member at the cinema, so I can get two tickets for one.
我是电影院的会员 买两张电影票只要付一张的钱
Then I'm in!
那我要去
Really?
真的吗？
I'm also interested in Director Yamada now.
我现在对山田导演也有兴趣了
Exciting, isn't it?
期待吧？
Yes.
对
Please do something.
请你想想办法
I want to get released and watch Director Kyohei's new movie.
让我赶快获释 我很想去看恭兵导演的新片
That director is getting flamed right now.
那位导演现在被乡民骂翻了
Did he make a faux pas?
他失言了吗？
No.
没有
People think he uploaded the fast movies because your names are similar
只是因为你们的名字很像 网络乡民以为是他上传快电影的
and are criticizing him.
所以都跑去骂他
As if!
骗人的吧
I'm telling you the truth!
我是说真的
You're lying to make me feel sorry, aren't you?
你是为了让我反省才骗我的吧？
Fast movies were appreciated.
大家都很喜欢快电影
No one would criticize them.
没有人会批评
I give up.
我放弃了
I won't come here anymore.
我不会再来会面了
You can just stay remorseless until the verdict.
你就这样一直毫无悔意 直到判决那天吧
Going to jail may be a good experience.
进监狱体验一下也不错
Huh? Can a lawyer act like this?
什么？律师摆出这种态度可以吗？
I'm only following your wishes.
我只是遵照你的意愿
We should both give up to the fact that we met under unrefusable circumstances.
我们都放弃吧 毕竟是 在无法拒绝的情况下才认识的
Hey!
喂！
I'll see you in court then.
法庭上见了
Am I not good enough?
难道我不行吗？
It was pretty empty even though there was a stage greeting.
即使有上映见面会 观众还是那么少
Yeah.
是啊
So, what do you want to do now?
你接下来要做什么？
I don't have any plans after this.
我之后是没什么计划啦
That man.
那位先生
Over there.
在那边
Right?
对吧？
What a terrible first day.
第一天的票房也太惨了
Those slanders may have given it a bad image.
可能是因为那些诽谤中伤 影响到形象了吧
I'm sorry to disturb you.
不好意思打扰各位
Your movie was great. Two hours went by so fast.
电影非常好看 两个小时很快就过去了
Thank you.
谢谢
Can I get your autograph?
可以帮我签名吗？
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
I know people are saying things on Twitter and stuff,
现在很多人在推特或什么的 说了很多奇怪的话
but please don't mind it.
请您不要介意
We fans are always here for you.
我们这些影迷会永远支持你的
I think this is a chance for me
我倒认为这是个机会
to reflect on myself.
让我能重新省思
I value futility and vagueness.
我很重视徒劳和暧昧的主题
And those are the kind of movies I make.
一直都在拍这样的电影
The complete opposite of fast movies.
跟快电影背道而驰
But if that's not what society wants,
不过 如果这不是大家想要看的
I'll just be weeded out.
我终究会被淘汰的
Your movies won't be weeded out.
导演的电影是不会被淘汰的
Hey.
嘿
Excuse me.
不好意思
To think that he's dealing with it so calmly
想到他这么冷静地接受这种情况
makes this even sadder, doesn't it?
反而让人更感到悲伤
I've become his fan including his personality.
包括他的人品在内 我已经变成他的粉丝了
Right?
对吧？
Director Yamada is awesome.
山田导演很赞吧
Do you wanna go to dinner?
要不要去吃晚餐？
Sorry, I'm going home today.
对不起 我今天先回去了
Oh, okay.
好
I want to watch his other movies.
我想看看山田导演的其他作品
I have all his movies, so I'll lend them to you.
这样的话 我有导演的全套作品 可以借你
Are you sure?
确定吗？
Yes.
对
I'll get them and bring them to your house.
你回家等我 我回去拿 马上拿去给你
No, wait. Mr. Oba. That's too much trouble for you.
等一下 大庭先生 这样太麻烦你了
So, um…
嗯…
Can I go to your place with you?
我跟你一起去你家吧？
What?
什么？
Well, but…
可是…
My room is a mess.
我的房间很乱
I won't be entering your room.
我不会进你房间
Oh, right.
对
Of course.
说得也是
Is your room that messy?
你房间有那么乱吗？
No, just untidy.
没有 只是不太整洁
-Like you can't see the floor? -You can.
-没有可以站的地方吗？ -当然有
Food on the floor?
满地食物？
I'm not a hoarder. Just normal untidiness.
我不是囤积狂 只是正常的不整洁
A FEW DAYS LATER
（数日后）
Hello everyone. Let me introduce Kyohei Yamada's latest movie,
大家好 今天要介绍的是 山田恭兵的全新作品
Tainted Towing today.
《污秽的曳航》
What is this?
这是怎么回事？
This is his latest movie.
这可是恭兵导演的新片
Someone uploaded a ten-minute summary video of Tainted Towing.
有人把《污秽的曳航》 压缩成10分钟的短片 然后上传
Oh dear. Maybe they copied Ryohei Yamada.
天啊 这是在模仿山田辽平吗？
Who would do this?
谁会干这种事？
The original video was reported immediately and has been deleted.
原始的视频立刻遭到检举 所以删除了
But the copied video is already all over the internet.
不过备份视频已经传遍全网了
"No need to watch the movie now." "A publicity stunt."
“不用再看电影了” “宣传花招吗？”
"Maybe the director did this himself."
“不会是导演在自导自演吧”
Saying what they like.
还真是口无遮拦哪
Damn it.
可恶
Shoichi had feelings for Sonoko. But Sonoko had a fiancé called Minoru.
昭一对园子倾心 但园子已经有名字叫实的未婚夫了
One day, Shoichi noticed a bruise on Shoko's arm.
有一天 昭一看到园子手腕上有瘀血
SHOKO WAS LIVING IN FEAR BECAUSE SHE WAS A VICTIM OF MINORU'S DOMESTIC VIOLENCE.
（未婚夫实对园子家暴 让她每天都生活在恐惧之中）
SEEING HOW WORN OUT SHE IS BY MINORU'S VIOLENCE, SHOICHI RUSHES OVER TO SHOKO.
（看到园子因为实的暴力对待而憔悴 昭一跑去找园子）
Shoichi, who realized something, took her to a shrine
了解状况之后的昭一 把园子带到神社
and tried to convince her to elope with him.
想要说服园子和他一起私奔
Minoru finds them and comes after them.
结果被实发现 追了上来
Why did this happen?
为什么会发生这种事？
Sonoko runs, but trips and falls.
园子逃跑 结果绊了一跤 摔倒了
The movie might get canceled.
搞不好要提早下架了
I spent ten years on it
耗费十年心血的结果
and this is it, huh?
就是这样吗？
Let's find out who did this.
我们来调查是谁干的吧
To clear the director's name.
也可以洗刷对导演的误解
Just leave it.
别管了
There's no need if there's no request.
没有人委托 所以没必要查
We can't take the case anyway.
就算有委托 我们也没办法接
What?
什么？
Director Kyohei Yamada is also the victim of the case Mr. Haneoka is defending.
山田恭兵导演也是羽根冈律师 这次辩护案件的受害者
When the same firm
当事人利害关系对立的案件
take on cases from conflicting parties, it's called "conflict of interest"
由同一个律所承接 会形成“利益冲突”
and it's prohibited by the law.
法律明文禁止
So, we should just give up?
难道我们要什么都不做 就这样直接放弃吗？
That's right.
没错
Even if we don't, it's not like Ryohei Yamada will get a suspended sentence.
就算去调查了 山田辽平也争取不到缓刑
Shoko.
硝子
I'm going out for a drink with Mr. Matsuda.
我要去跟松田喝一杯
Sure, have fun.
好 喝得开心点
If you're wondering what you can do for the director,
如果你是在想 有什么可以帮上导演的方法
why don't you refer him to a lawyer at another firm?
不是可以帮他介绍 其他律所的律师吗？
I thought that too.
我也想过
But we won't get a penny.
但这样我们一毛钱也拿不到
That would be the same as what you're doing.
这样跟爸爸做的事情有什么不一样
But then, we can't charge him for it either.
可是 我们又不能借此收费
Why not look at the bigger picture?
你眼光放远一点
Referring him will improve our firm's reputation.
帮他介绍律师 可以提升我们律所的名声
Then, maybe we'll get more requests and make more profit.
说不定能因此拿到更多委托 赚到更多利润啊
But there's no guarantee of that.
但这种事情又不能保证
Well, yeah.
对哦
But the defendant is a fan of Director Yamada, right?
可是…被告是山田导演的粉丝吧？
Yes.
对
If we can help the director, he might hear out our defense strategy.
我们帮导演的话 说不定他会听从我们的辩护方针
You're right.
你说得对
That would benefit the firm and it's not against my rules.
这样对我们律所也有好处 并没有违反我的原则
Thank you very much.
非常感谢
-Looks good. -Yes, it does.
-看起来真好吃 -就是啊
Let's eat.
我要开动了
Looks delicious. Is this sea bream?
看起来很美味 是鲷鱼吗？
Looks like it.
应该是
Yeah, let me try.
来吃吃看
-How is it? -Well…
-怎么样？ -嗯…
I'm so happy I get to celebrate my birthday
今年也是让全家人帮我过生日
with my family again this year.
我真是太幸福了
Honey, you're always smiling.
亲爱的 你总是笑容满面
Yuno, your success always inspires me.
优乃的活跃表现总是带给我不少刺激
Happy birthday.
生日快乐
Yoshio, you always…
佳男也总是…
manage to surprise me.
让我感到很惊讶
Yuno told me about your current firm.
优乃跟我说了 你现在任职于什么样的律所
I didn't think you'd be a local lawyer.
没想到你会在当地的律所工作
So you chose to tread a thorny path.
你选择了一条充满荆棘的道路
Hats off to you.
真是佩服
I'm sure any firm would've wanted Yoshio in their team.
我相信各大律所 都会想要邀佳男加入的
-Dad. -Huh?
-爸 -怎么了？
I've heard your story.
我听说你的事了
After you got kicked out of our company, no one wanted to hire you, right?
你被我们踢出去之后 没有其他律所想雇用你吧？
As I said before,
我先前就说过了
I was asked to resign because I couldn't achieve any results.
我是因为做不出任何成果 才会被先前的律所要求辞职的
That rumor spread and no one--
这件事也传开来了…
That's not true.
没这回事
Who wouldn't want someone who's as talented as you?
像你这样的人才 谁不会想要争取呢？
-Dad-- -You…
-爸… -你啊…
You do not lose to anyone.
是不会输给任何人的
I've witnessed your talent since you were a child.
从你小时候 我就看得出来你是很有才能的
You're a genius.
你是天才
And that hasn't changed.
直到现在也没有改变
You are capable.
你很能干
Take care.
保重
Thank you.
谢谢
You're really socially awkward, aren't you?
你真的不擅长社交 对吧？
Why couldn't you just go with it?
顺着他的意思不就好了
He only sees what he wants to see and hears what he wants to hear.
他只看他想看的东西 只听他想听的话
You know that.
你也知道吧
Here's your cab.
车来了
-Bye. -Yeah.
-再见 -好
Oh, hey. He doesn't seem to be sorry at all, huh?
喂 他好像毫无悔意 对吧？
Huh?
什么？
I heard about that horrible guy in the devil T-shirt.
大家都在传 穿恶魔T恤那家伙太恶劣了
But actually, what's the problem?
可到底是哪里的问题？
What's wrong with fast movies?
快电影有什么问题吗？
Fast movies were appreciated.
大家都很喜欢快电影
He may not get a suspended sentence.
可能争取不到缓刑了吧
Are you gonna be okay?
你没问题吧？
I mean, you're bad at trials to begin with.
即使不是这个案件 你也很不擅长上法庭
Okay then, good night.
那就这样了 晚安
Thank you.
谢谢
Hello?
喂？
I'm sorry to call you so late. Do you have time to talk?
不好意思这么晚打给你 现在方便讲话吗？
Yeah.
可以
Okay.
好
I was thinking of referring another lawyer to Director Yamada, if he wants.
如果山田导演想要的话 我想要帮忙介绍其他律所的律师
Oh, that.
这件事啊
Fine. Do as you wish.
随便你吧
Sorry for the trouble, but could you ask Mr. Ryohei Yamada if he's okay with it?
不好意思 不过可能要麻烦你 去跟山田辽平先生确认不会有问题
No way. I'm not going to visit him.
不要 我不会去跟他会面了
Don't say that. I need you to go.
不要这么说 你就去嘛
Hey, I was wondering…
我问你…
Yes?
什么？
Why did you choose this job?
为什么会想要做这份工作？
Is it because of your dad?
是受你爸的影响吗？
Well,
这个嘛
I guess so.
应该是吧
He told you to choose this path?
他让你选择法律这条路？
Seeing my dad work got me interested.
看到爸爸工作的样子 让我产生兴趣
Like removing the thorns from the hearts of his clients,
对于来咨询的客人 能够帮他们解决心头的难题
being able to help the victims
对于受害者或是罪犯
and those who committed a crime to start over
也能帮助他们重新开始
just seemed wonderful.
我觉得是很棒的工作
Even if someone made a mistake and lost everything,
就算曾经跌倒了 失去一切
that person's life still goes on.
当事人的人生还是要继续
To be able to help them sprout and grow again is one of the reasons
能够帮助他们再次发芽 成长茁壮
I wanted to be a lawyer.
所以我想当老师
Well, I'm not a lawyer though.
虽然我并不是律师啦
So, that is your true nature.
果然这才是你的本质
What?
什么？
That money-loving character is only a pretense.
爱钱的个性只是假装出来的
Right? You sound just like your father.
对吧？你说的话跟所长一模一样
I'm not like him.
我才不像我爸
I'm a money grubber.
我就是嗜财如命
People usually don't call themselves that.
一般人才不会说自己嗜财如命
Anyway, is something wrong?
无论如何 发生什么事了？
Huh?
嗯？
You usually only seem to be interested in yourself,
我以为你只对自己有兴趣
but you're asking me these questions.
刚刚却问我那样的问题
It's nothing.
没什么
No reason.
没别的意思
Oh. Okay.
哦 好吧
About what you said.
你刚刚说的那件事
Huh?
什么？
I guess I can ask him.
我去问问他吧
Ryohei Yamada.
山田辽平
Really?
真的吗？
You want me to, right?
你不是要我去吗？
Yes!
对
What do you say when you ask someone for a favor?
有求于人的时候 应该要说什么？
Please help me out.
麻烦帮帮我
Okay.
好
I'm hanging up now.
那我挂电话了
Good night.
晚安
But we're pretty tight too.
但我们也是过得紧巴巴的
Mr. Kurahashi is reliable and I'm sure he's open to discussing the fee.
仓桥律师很值得信赖 费用的部分也可以讨论
Hello.
-你好
I'd like to thank you on behalf of the fans.
我想要代表粉丝感谢你
No need. I've become his fan too.
不用啦 我现在也是粉丝了
Which one did you like?
你最喜欢哪一部？
My favorite is--
我最喜欢的是…
Sorry. Can we continue this when I come back from court?
不好意思 可以等我从法院回来 再继续聊吗？
Chief asked me to file a complaint.
所长请我去送诉状
Go ahead. No need to rush.
你去吧 不用急没关系
Okay, I'll hurry without rushing then.
好 我会不急不忙地赶过去
I'll be off.
我出门了
See you later.
回见
I guess I'll go too.
那我也要出门了
Where to?
要去哪里？
To the interview.
去会面
I decided not to give up on making him feel remorse.
我决定不要放弃 要想办法让他反省
Not only for my social media.
不只是为了平息对我的抨击
Shoichi reciprocated her feelings.
昭一也想要回应她的心意
Got it.
明白
They kept running and ended up on a beach.
两人一路逃跑 最后来到了海边
Stop!
停
IS THERE HAPPINESS ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THE OCEAN?
（幸福会在大海的另一边 等着他们两人吗？）
This scene…
这一幕…
I wanted to protect you all along.
我想要一直保护你
I would die with you.
只要能跟你在一起 死不足惜
Could you check the editing?
可以请你确认一下剪辑吗？
Sure.
好
Sorry to keep you waiting.
抱歉让你久等了
Do you do the editing here?
你们是在这里进行剪辑吗？
For some of them. We usually send it to the editorial office.
一般是会送到剪辑公司 不过有些会自己剪辑
How can I help you?
有什么事吗？
I was thinking that maybe you have an idea
上传《污秽的曳航》快电影的人
who uploaded the fast movie of Tainted Towing.
您会不会其实心里有数？
Please take a look at this.
请您看一下
This scene…
这一幕…
It wasn't there when I watched it at the cinema.
我在电影院看的时候没有这一幕啊
You watched it?
你看过电影了？
Well, the defendant is a fan. So I thought it would help.
被告说他是粉丝 我想说看了说不定会有帮助
Meaning, there are unused scenes included in this fast movie.
也就是说 这支快电影里面 出现了正片没有采用的画面
There's no way you didn't notice that.
导演不可能没发现
I believe there's only a handful of people
能接触到未采用画面的人
who has access to unused scenes.
我想应该不多吧
Would you like to step out of the office?
要不要出去走走？
The guy who was in the next room.
在隔壁办公室的那个人
His name is Moroboshi and he's very passionate about movies.
他叫诸星 是个对电影很有热情的人
It all started when he ambushed me here
一开始是他在这里等我
and begged me to hire him as an assistant director.
拜托我让他当助理导演
I think it's him
上传视频的人
who uploaded the video.
应该是他
On opening night,
首映那天晚上
we went out for a drink and he was complaining
我们去喝酒时他一直在抱怨
how small the audience was.
来看电影的人实在太少了
"If only we could get them to see it."
“只要看了电影 一定会很喜欢
"We should do whatever we can to promote it. Even fast movies."
就算是利用快电影也好 应该要想尽办法宣传”
He spat those words out and left.
他说完这些话就回去了
The video was uploaded right after that.
没多久视频就上传了
He did it for the sake of the movie, but in the end…
他是为了电影才这样做 结果…
I don't know
我不知道
how he feels about all this.
他对这件事是怎么想的
But the reviews of the movie are all my responsibility.
不过电影的评价 责任全在我
I don't think it became
我认为
a box-office failure only because of that video.
不会光因为那个视频就造成票房失利
On second thought, can I cancel the lawyer?
委托律师的事现在还能取消吗？
My team's misconduct
自己人闯的祸
should be dealt with within the team.
就应该要自己解决
I was going to tell him that I watched the movie,
我原本想跟他说我看过导演的电影了
but he wouldn't even listen saying he won't be convinced.
但他说“无论你说什么都没用” 根本不听我讲话
It's hard to confront someone who won't accept anything.
面对什么话都不肯听的对象 实在太痛苦了
The questioning of the defendant is tomorrow, you know.
被告问讯就是明天
I'm out of ideas.
已经没办法了
We're doomed.
太绝望了
You'll be famous if he doesn't get a suspended sentence.
要是争取不到缓刑的话 你会变得很有名
In a negative way.
我是说臭名
I know, right?
我想也是
I thought about it too.
我也想过了
How to make him face his sins.
要怎么做 才能让他愿意面对自己的罪恶
I think this is the only way.
我想只有这个办法了
Do you want to hear it?
想听吗？
What do you say when you ask someone for a favor?
有求于人的时候 应该要说什么？
Please…
拜托…
Huh? What?
嗯？什么？
Pardon?
你说什么？
Oh, excuse me.
不好意思
I forgot to tell you one thing.
有件事我忘记问了
Um…
那个…
Have you memorized the possible arguments for tomorrow?
你已经记住明天的模拟问答了吗？
There's no need.
没那个必要
I'll tell them how I feel in my own words.
我会用自己的话表达自己的想法
Okay.
最后呢
Then, as my final request, could you take a look at this?
最后可以请你看一下这个吗？
First, you'll show him this video.
首先 请他看这个视频
That's the end.
播完了
This is a fast movie of Director Yamada's latest movie.
这是山田恭兵导演 最新力作的快电影版
The one you were looking forward to.
你原本很想进电影院看的那部
Someone uploaded this video and it's causing a controversy.
有人把这个视频上传到网络 引发了不少问题
Who did this?
犯人是谁？
We don't know.
不知道
That person is messing with the movie.
那家伙简直是在恶搞
It's such a low-quality fast movie.
这么低水平的快电影
The sensitive psychological portrait and its unique sense of excitement.
恭兵导演的电影 细腻的心理描写 以及不知道接下来会如何发展的
That's what makes Director Yamada's movies appealing.
独特的期待感 这些才是最吸引人的地方
But if you edit it like this, it'll ruin that quality.
被乱剪成这样 根本无法传达出电影的优点
It took away the anticipation of watching the full movie.
这根本剥夺了 观众看完一整部电影的乐趣
That's what you did.
这就是你先前在做的事啊
No, I received comments saying it made them want to watch--
才不是 很多人留言说 看了我的视频才想去看电影
And I wonder how many of them actually watched the movie.
觉得想看但真正去看电影的人 到底有多少呢？
Aren't there more people who didn't bother after watching the video?
难道不是有更多人 看完视频后不想去看电影吗？
There are way too many cons than pros.
反对者远多于支持者
Moreover, if the producer doesn't wish for it, it is wrong.
而且如果创作者不乐见这种事 那就是错误的行为
Even if you did it for the sake of the movie.
不管你立意多么良好也一样
Unfortunately, the screening of Director Yamada's new movie
非常遗憾 山田导演的新片
has been terminated.
已经提早下片了
What?
什么？
Maybe the online reviews had something to do with it too.
网络上的观影心得应该也有影响吧
There weren't many audiences…
进电影院的观众那么少
…but there are many reviews online.
影评网站上的心得却非常多
And they're all bad reviews.
而且全都是差评
I did a little digging and the majority were
我稍微研究了一下 大多数人是受到差评影响
people criticizing without having seen the movie
连电影都没看就跑上去骂
and those commenting only after watching the fast movie.
还有人只看了快电影就发表评论 这些人占了大多数
They're rating it based on the video alone?
只看了这个视频就评分了吗？
It seems so.
好像是这样
I guess they think they've watched the movie.
不过他们应该是觉得自己看过电影了
They think a ten-minute video is enough to understand the whole movie.
看了十分钟的视频 就觉得看过电影了 这样就满足了
They criticize everything based on headlines of online articles alone.
只看了网络报道的标题 任意地发出批评
They don't bother going through the contents because…
根本不想费心去了解其中的内容 因为…
…it's a waste of time.
那样很浪费时间
Those who praised you…
那些吹捧你的人
…aren't going to take any responsibility. Rather…
并没有人打算要负责 相反地
…they crushed the work that took ten years to complete in a flash.
还让导演耗费十年的作品毁于一旦
Director Yamada mortgaged his house in Suginami to raise 22 million yen.
山田导演抵押了他在杉并区的住宅 贷款2200万
He raised 13 million yen borrowing money from people.
还向各方低头 筹到了1300万
And he covers half of the production costs himself.
制作费有一半是他自掏腰包
The other half is paid by the production company.
另一半则是制片公司出的
He also had to beg the actors…
他还去低头请求演员
…to perform in the movie for a very low fee.
请他们降低演出费
But it turned out like this…
结果却变成这样
…making everyone who worked on this movie suffer.
让参与电影制作的每个人都很痛苦
Now, do you have an idea of how sinful this "fast" world is?
你参与其中的“快电影”世界 罪孽有多深重
The one you took part in?
你现在知道了吗？
That's all.
我说完了
SECOND TRIAL
（第二次公审）
Is there anything else you'd like to say?
你最后有什么话要说吗？
Yes.
有
I know it's too late,
虽然为时已晚
but I really think what I did was disgraceful.
但我真心觉得自己做的事情好丢脸
I thought I was doing it for the movie,
我以为这么做是为了电影好
but I was completely wrong.
结果全然不是这么一回事
But if I could ever be forgiven
但是 如果还可以的话
I'd like to be involved with movies again.
我希望还能够从事电影相关工作
The defendant is sentenced to one year and two months…
判处被告一年零两个月有期徒刑
The execution of this sentence is suspended for three years
本判决自审判结束之日起
from the day the trial is finalized.
缓期执行三年
Thank goodness. I'm so glad you got a suspended sentence.
谢天谢地 能够缓刑真是太好了
You cared so much for me.
你们太关照我了
What a relief.
谢谢你们为我做了这么多
I'm sorry about everything.
我对这一切感到很抱歉
Me too. I'm sorry.
我也要跟你道歉
You wanted to watch the movie, but I showed you the video.
你那么想进电影院看 我却让你看了那部视频
No, that brought me to my senses.
不会 我是因为这样才清醒的
Shall we go then?
我们走吧？
Yes.
好
Excuse me!
不好意思
Could you come with me?
可以陪我去个地方吗？
I'm sorry to call you out here.
真不好意思 把你叫出来
Director, he's…
导演 这位是…
I'm terribly sorry!
真的非常抱歉
I don't expect you to forgive me, but I wanted to apologize to you in person.
我不期望你会原谅我 但无论如何都想当面跟你致歉
You see,
你看
I'm a slow writer and I think too much,
我写得很慢 又想得太多
so I need a lot of time.
需要很多时间
I'm far from getting a general blockbuster hit,
我的作品又不是一般的卖座电影
so I can't get sponsors.
一直筹不到钱
So, I need at least seven years.
最少也要七年
For this movie, it took me ten years.
这一次 花了我十年
And I realized, I've turned 65.
一不留神我就已经65岁了
If the next one will also take ten years,
如果要再花十年
I may not be able to make another movie.
说不定就没办法再拍电影了
I'm sorry for my immaturity.
很抱歉 我没那么宽容大量
But no matter how much you apologize,
不管你怎么向我道歉
I cannot accept it.
我都没办法接受
I wonder if we were able to help anyone this time.
不知道这次我们有没有帮到任何人
Who knows.
谁知道呢
Maybe this became a deterrent for future crimes.
对于未来的犯罪 多少有一点威慑效果吧
And I guess the rest is up to Ryohei Yamada from here on.
再来就看山田辽平今后要怎么做了
I guess so.
也是
Geez.
老天
It's already summer, huh?
夏天到了吗？
Yes.
对
I haven't had the time to look up at the sky.
最近都没空看看天空啊
I've been busy, like moving to a new firm.
换了律所 工作一大堆
So? Have you gotten used to the office?
怎么样？习惯了吗？
I'm not sure. The paralegal there is hard-headed.
说不好 那个律师助理很精明
Oh, I'm sorry.
不好意思
But I'm grateful.
不过我很感谢你
Just a little.
只有一点点
You've helped me a little.
你稍微帮了一点点忙
Maybe you don't need to pretend to be a genius anymore.
应该不需要再假装是天才了吧？
I feel that you're competent enough, Mr. Haneoka.
我觉得羽根冈律师是非常有能力的
So…
所以…
It's fine. This is my branding.
没关系 这是我的品牌形象
In the criminal trial, he is found guilty of violating the Copyright Act.
刑事诉讼判决 违反著作权法有罪定案
13 film companies and TV stations
由电影公司和电视台共13家公司
filed a lawsuit to the Tokyo District Court claiming 500 million yen
针对快电影提出侵害著作权诉讼
in compensation for copyright infringement by fast movies.
求偿五亿日圆一案 在东京地方法院开庭
The defendant is going viral.
被告的信息被人大量转发
The photo of him when he was charged.
移送检方时的照片也贴得到处都是
This will affect his future, whatever he decides to do.
不管他决定以后怎么生活 这都会有影响吧
I guess today, you get other kinds of punishment on top of the law's judgment.
现在不只是会受到法律审判 也会受到其他的惩罚啊
The victims remain as well.
受到伤害的人也会继续受到影响
The comments of those who misunderstood the director remains
误会了导演而胡乱批评 那些留言也会留下来
and will remain that way.
导演也会继续遭到误解
That's awful.
太可怕了
A digital tattoo, indeed.
真的是数码纹身
Once information spreads online, it can't be deleted completely.
信息一旦在网络上传开了 就永远删不掉了
The director…
导演说
After Mr. Moroboshi admitted to releasing the video,
诸星先生承认自己上传了那个视频
he fired him.
所以把他开除了
Maybe it's out of love that he didn't file a lawsuit.
没有起诉他或许是出于疼爱吧
To let him have a proper fresh start.
不让他重新出发的芽折损
I didn't hit and run.
我没有肇事逃逸
I almost died because of the hit-and-run.
她肇事逃逸 我差点就没命了
Where's your confidence, Mr. Lawyer?
说那什么丧气话 你这位律师？
I'll be prosecuting.
我要起诉
See you in court.
法庭上见吧
I want to prove that my sister isn't lying.
我想证明我妹妹没有说谎
Enough already.
已经足够了
I think I wasn't determined enough.
应该是不够坚决吧
Subtitle translation by: Aya Kudo
字幕翻译：赤焰